Michael Stokley

michael@michaelstokley.com (303) 801-8575 Seattle, WA linkedin.com/in/mastokley github.com/mastokley michaelstokley.com

Profile

Independent, self-motivated individual who places a high value on remaining engaged and challenged. As night shift data entry clerk, I involved myself in as many additional projects as possible, such as video review and 'closing misses'; as AR Specialist, I taught myself intermediate SQL, which permitted me to overhaul our billing and service history reports as well as automate or streamline many data entry / data quality processes. In both positions I greatly exceeded the expectations set by both the stated job description and by my predecessors. I look forward to meeting new challenges, growing as an employee, and contributing in a new position at your organization.

Technical Skills

Proficient

Python, Django, Pyramid, SQL, HTML/CSS, Relational Database Theory, Debian, Bash

Familiar

JavaScript, jQuery, AWS Deployment, Heroku Deployment, Ansible, Postgres, Scheme

Education

Code Fellows, Seattle, WA, 2016

Certificate, Advanced Python Development

North Seattle College, Seattle, WA, 2012 - 2014

Two years of math, statistics, and CS coursework

St. John's College, Annapolis, MD, 2009

B. A. in Philosophy

Projects

"Reciprocity", 2016.04

- source at github.com/TeamReciprocity/reciprocity; live site at reciprocity.michaelstokley.com
- < one-line description >
- built with Django and Postgres, deployed via Ansible on an AWS EC2 instance
- < responsibilities and accomplishments >
- < highlight the portions of specifically owned >

"HomeQuest", 2016.03

- web app to gamify household chores and chore management
- manually implemented authorization, authentication as well as row-level security
- built with Pyramid and Postgres, deployed on Heroku
- source at github.com/homequest; live site at homequest.michaelstokley.com

Learning Journal, 2016.03

- lightweight personal blog
- built with Pyramid and Postgres, deployed on Heroku
- source at github.com/mastokley/learning journal; live site at learning journal.michaelstokley.com

Experience

Recology CleanScapes

AR Specialist, 2012.04 - 2015.04

- Oversaw and coordinated all billing and collections activities
- Developed accurate, sophisticated SQL queries to capture evolving data inconsistencies. These queries eliminated ~37.5 hours of labor per month despite a 126% increase in customer accounts over two years
- Designed database reports for internal and external customers, such as government officials and senior management
- Delegated data entry / data revision tasks
- Collaborated with operations, data quality, payment processing, and customer service teams to analyze and improve processes as new city contracts were won
- Closed the month on a deadline

Data Quality Specialist, 2011.07 - 2012.04 Various data entry; dispatch and 'front desk'/customer service duties for graveyard shift; reviewed truck video for misses and accidents; 'closing' misses; illegal dumping reporting for SPU; various clerical, reporting, and recordkeeping duties

Kojen English Language School in Taipei, Taiwan

ESL Teacher, **2009.10** - **2010.10** Taught high energy ESL classes for children aged 5 - 18; resolved classroom conflicts; planned lessons and coordinated lesson plans with co-teachers; prepared end of class student grade reports